(Disodium Hydrogen Phosphate   Iron Oxide)
磷酸氢二钠  氧化铁
ALIVE
存活
Hello? It's me. Can you come here for a minute?
喂  是我  你能来一下吗
Yes. That's right. Lab No. 4.
嗯  对  在第四实验室
I have something interesting to show you.
给你看点有意思的东西
Right.
是啊
The smell?
气味？
I didn't smell anything.
我可没有嗅到那样的气味
We are just like sharks.
和鲨鱼是一个道理
We pick up the scent of blood, hurry to the crime scene,
嗅到血的气味后奔赴现场
and use every sense we have to find the culprit.
动用五感来揪出犯人
Once they've taken the bait, we sink our razor-sharp teeth known as "evidence"
一旦咬住犯人  就用名为证据的尖牙
into their flesh until they confess.
紧紧咬到对方承认罪行
That's what a detective does.
这就是侦探
Detective Conan
名侦探柯南
(Case Closed Episode "One" The Great Detective Turned Small)
真·第一集     变小了的名侦探
Isn't it better to give up on this?
果然还是放弃比较好吧
I mean having your big surprise reunion and romance revival plan
在发生了杀人案的水族馆
at an aquarium where a murder took place.
进行惊喜重逢  爱情复活大作战什么的
Well, you have a point.
说的也是啊
Oh, it's starting to rain.
不好  下雨了
So it is.
真的呢
Then, let's run back home.
那我们跑回去吧
Ah? Hey! I told you not to run!
啊  喂  我不是都叫你不要跑了吗
Why? Why shouldn't I?
所以？为什么不能跑
Are you kidding me? Why was my phone in my hood?
不会吧  为什么我的手机会在兜帽里
Err, sorry!
啊  抱歉
I was trying to figure out where the killer put the phone to record a video like that,
我之前在思考  犯人究竟是把手机放在了哪里才能够拍摄出那段视频
and I forgot I left the phone in your hood.
把手机放进你的兜帽之后就忘记了
How are you going to pay me back? My dad just bought it for me!
你要怎么赔我啊  那可是我爸爸新买给我的
D-Don't cry!
别  别哭了
I'll buy you a new one in a few days.
我过几天再买一个赔你吧
Shinichi, you're terrible!
新一最坏了
Nothing good ever happens when I'm with you!
和新一待在一起总是没好事
Even when we were in the U.S., we did nothing but handle cases!
去美国的时候也总是遇到案件
Alright! Then...
我知道啦  那么…
I'll take you
多罗碧加热带乐园
to Tropical Land.
我带你去那里玩吧
Tropical Land?
多罗碧加热带乐园？
What's that place? It sounds fun!
是什么地方啊  听起来很好玩的样子
Yeah! It's due to be completed soon in Tokyo!
是啊  最近就要在东京落成了
And I certainly don't expect any cases to turn up at an amusement park.
那样的游乐园里应该不会发生什么案件了吧
If it's your treat, I'd love to go with you.
要是新一请客的话  我倒是可以奉陪
Then let's go there if I win the regional karate tournament, okay?
那如果我在空手道都大赛中拿到冠军的话就去  怎么样
Hey, wait a second. You were the runner-up last year, weren't you?
喂  等一下  去年你是亚军吧
And isn't the senior who won
而且得冠军的高三学姐
about to retire from the club?
不是也要退出社团了吗
It's a deal!
我们说好了哦
But I don't have much of an allowance.
我零花钱可是很少的啊
And, when you buy me a new phone,
还有  你要是给我买手机的话
remember to put a "sea cucumber man" strap sold at the Beika Aquarium on it!
记得还要附带一个米花水族馆海参男孩的挂件
Yeah! Got it!
好  好
And then...
还有就是
What? There's more?
诶  怎么还有啊
Well, I'll let you off for now.
那  暂且就这样饶过你吧
Thanks!
多谢多谢
Wow, it's pouring!
哎呀  雨还真大啊
The forecast was way off!
预报真是太不准了
I'll have what he's having.
我和他要一样的酒
You're not gonna check?
你不确认一下里面的东西吗
Hmph! If it's fake, I'll have you pay with your life.
哼  要是假货的话  就用你的命来抵吧
I'm going to check.
我这边可是要确认一下
Suit yourself.
随便你
Okay. It's all here.
OK  没问题
Sorry to keep you waiting.
让您久等了
So, what's my next job?
那么  下一个工作是？
There's got to be something you can tell me.
我总得知道一点下次工作的情况吧
Did you know about that?
那  你知道吗
It seems there's a rat that's been nosing
最近好像有老鼠在偷偷地
around our organization lately.
四处打探关于组织的事
What do you think of that?
你怎么看
I...I had no idea!
我  我不知道
I'd not heard anything like that.
没有听说过啊
Really?
是吗
So, my next job is to find out the rat you just mentioned?
那下次的工作就是找出你说的那只老鼠吗
No. I already know that rat's identity.
不  老鼠的身份我心里已经有数了
This cocktail is delicious!
这酒  真好喝啊
What's in it?
是用什么酒调的
Rum.
朗姆
Cointreau.
君度
A bit of lemon juice.
再加少许柠檬汁
X, Y, Z.
X  Y  Z
It's a drink called "This is the end."
这就叫做「最后一杯酒」
L-Let me know when you have a job for me.
那  那么下次还有工作的话记得通知我
Is that okay, boss?
这样可以吗  大哥
Just letting him leave like that?
就这么不声不响地放他走了
He's obviously the rat, isn't he?
那个家伙毫无疑问就是老鼠吧
Mmm.
嗯
It'll be fine.
没关系
It's a drink called "This is the end."
这就叫做「最后一杯酒」
It's me.
是我
Understood. We'll leave immediately.
知道了  立刻隐蔽
So, boss, what do we do with this?
那大哥  要怎么处理
The file of the smuggled weapons.
这些枪支走私的资料
Don't worry about this. Just go ahead with the plan.
不用管这个  按原定计划进行
They've accepted the price
他们已经接受了
that we earnestly proposed, right?
那个充分体现我们诚意的报价了吧
Yes. But it could be a trap.
是的  但是这也有可能是陷阱
We should give him the benefit of doubt before we contacted him.
和对方接触后再判断是不是陷阱也不迟
I guess you're right.
说的也是啊
Besides,
而且
it'd be a shame to give up too soon.
要是在那里放弃就太可惜了
Who is it?
哪位
Shinichi?
新一？
Oh, it's you, Ran!
是小兰啊
What are you doing here so early?
这一大早的  怎么了
What are you talking about?
你在说什么呢
It's 11 already! 11!
现在已经十一点了  十一点
Eh? Seriously?
诶  真的假的
My goodness!
真是的
Sorry to bother you!
打扰了
So, what brings you here on a Sunday?
所以说你怎么来了  今天不是周日吗
You really forgot, didn't you?
你果然忘记了
Huh? About what?
嗯？有什么事吗
What do you mean, about what?
才不是有什么事呢
When I told you that I'd finally have a day off from karate practice,
之前跟你说  今天空手道练习好不容易能休息一天
you said, "Then let's go buy a new phone."
那咱们就去买手机吧
Don't you remember, Shinichi?
说这话的是新一你吧
I...I'm sorry! I completely forgot.
不  不好意思  我忘得一干二净了
Gosh, you stayed up late and read mysteries again, didn't you?
真是的  反正又是通宵看推理小说了吧
Hehehe! Bingo!
嘿嘿嘿  说中了
Anyway, hurry and get changed.
总之  你赶快去换衣服吧
I'll go cook something to fill you up in the meantime.
在这期间我去给你做点可以填饱肚子的东西
You haven't had breakfast, have you?
你还没吃早饭吧
Not yet. Thank you!
是啊  那谢谢啦
And listen! Don't forget the "sea cucumber man" strap!
听好了  不要忘了海参男孩的挂件哦
You bet!
明白
That's strange!
奇怪
The night we went to the aquarium last week,
上周我们去水族馆的那天夜里
a car near Beika Harbor exploded.
米花港口附近发生了汽车爆炸事故吧
Mmm.
嗯
So, what about it?
那起事故怎么了吗
It looks like it's still under investigation.
那起事故好像还没有查清原委
You're right! That's terrible!
真的啊  总觉得有点吓人呢
But I'm sure it'll be solved soon.
但是啊  肯定会马上查清的
Because Japan's police are amazing!
因为日本的警察很优秀啊
"And someone like me who's admired by the police is even more amazing!"
「备受那群优秀警察所青睐的我  就是超级优秀的了」
Isn't that what you want to say?
你是想说这个吧
Pretty much!
算是吧
Be humble for once, will you?
你能不能稍微谦虚一点啊
I was kidding. Just kidding!
只是开玩笑而已  开玩笑
Then, it's time to head out.
那差不多该出发了吧
Okay.
也是啊
Mitsuhiko-kun! Pass! Pass!
光彦  传球传球
Ayumi-chan!
步美
Here I go, Genta-kun!
我要踢咯  元太
I'm ready! Do it!
好的  来吧
Piece of cake! Piece of cake! Haha!
轻而易举  轻而易举  哈哈
I'm sorry, Ayumi-chan.
真可惜啊  步美
Alright! Now it's my turn!
那我也要踢过去了
Come on, Genta-kun!
喂喂  元太
Watch where you're kicking that, okay?
你在朝哪里踢啊
My bad! My bad!
抱歉抱歉
I'm sorry!
不好意思
Could you stop the ball for us?
请帮我们捡一下球
Wow! That's amazing!
哇  真厉害
Are you a soccer player?
你是足球选手吗
Yeah. I used to be.
是啊  我以前是
Here.
给你们
Thank you very much!
谢谢你
Bye-bye!
拜拜
If only we had a friend who's good at soccer like him,
如果有像那位哥哥一样足球踢得那么好的小伙伴
then we could get better, too!
我们的足球也能进步了吧
You're right!
是啊
If you hadn't quit the soccer club,
新一要是没有退出足球社的话
you might have become a member of the national team by now.
现在说不定已经是国家代表队的队员了
I'm only an 11th grader. It's too early for that.
我才高二  还早呢
Is it?
是吗
Besides, I only played soccer to build up the stamina
而且我只是为了锻炼作为侦探必须具备的运动神经
that a detective needs.
才去踢足球的
Look, Holmes also practiced fencing, right?
你看  福尔摩斯不是也练击剑吗
That's just a novel, though.
那是小说吧
But he's a famous detective that everyone around the world knows!
但是  他可是全世界家喻户晓的名侦探啊
That's true...
那倒也是
He's incredible!
他真是厉害
He's always calm and collected,
总是沉着冷静
overflowing with intelligence and refinement.
又不失知性与教养
And no one can top his abilities of observation and deduction.
观察能力和推理能力也是无人能及
Moreover, his violin skills are as good as a professional's.
再加上他拉小提琴的技术也是专业水平
Sherlock Holmes, created by novelist Sir Conan Doyle,
小说家柯南·道尔所创造的夏洛克·福尔摩斯
is the world's greatest detective!
是世界第一的名侦探哦
Someone! Catch him! He stole my purse!
谁来帮我捉住他  抢劫啊
Someone! Help!
谁来帮帮我
Outta my way!
让开  让开
Excuse me! Sorry!
请让一下  不好意思
Excuse me!
借过一下
Who the hell are you?
你这家伙是谁
Hina Wada, from Haido High, second year.
杯户高中二年级  和田阳奈
It's that girl...
那个女生
Come on, Ran, let's go and help her!
喂  小兰  我们过去吧  得帮帮她
There's no need! She's got it. Trust me.
不用了  是她的话  大概没问题的
Damn! How dare you mess with me?
可恶  敢妨碍老子  饶不了你
Oh? You've got a knife, huh?
哦？掏出刀了啊
Then I'll have to show you what I've got!
那我也要  拿出我的真本事啦
Karate?
空手道？
Shall I keep going?
还打吗
She's amazing!
好厉害
That girl seems pretty strong!
那个女生  看起来很强啊
Not just seems. She's truly strong!
不  她不是看起来强  而是真的强
And that was her first encounter with an unavoidable lifelong rival
那就是在空手道登峰造极后无法避免的
after reaching the highest karate level.
与人生劲敌的邂逅
Ran Mouri, 16 years old. It happened in the spring.
毛利兰  16岁  在这个春天里
Sonoko!
园子
Just kidding!
开玩笑的啦
What's with that impromptu narration?
什么啊  强行插入解说
And it's not even spring yet!
而且现在根本没到春天啊
So what? It helped set the mood, didn't it?
那有什么  重要的是气氛啊气氛
Besides, it's not my first encounter with her.
而且这也不是邂逅
What? You know her?
什么啊  你们认识啊
Yeah. We've met several times during competitions.
嗯  在比赛时见过几次
Anyway, Ran, would you come to my house?
比起这个  小兰  到我家来一下吧
But we are still going to...
但是  我们之后还要去…
You can always make time for a date!
约会什么时候不能约
Come on! Let's go!
走吧  走吧
Wait, Sonoko!
等等  园子
I'm back!
我回来了
Welcome home, Sonoko-sama.
欢迎回家  园子小姐
Here! Come in!
快  进来进来
Thank you for having us!
打扰了
Welcome, Mouri-sama, Kudo-sama.
欢迎光临  毛利小姐  工藤先生
I got the Soft 'n Fluffy Cheese Tarts
今天啊  有从北海道寄来的
delivered from Hokkaido today.
「香软起司挞」哦
The cheese tarts with a three-month waiting list to reserve?
那个预约之后还要等三个月的起司挞吗
Yep! Let's enjoy them together!
对啊  一起来吃吧
Okay! Great!
好呀好呀
Are you sure about that?
这样真的好吗
Eating sweets before the championship?
在大赛前吃那么多
Don't complain about it if you gain weight.
要是吃胖了我可不管哦
It's fine. I heard Kazumi-senpai will join us for practice tomorrow.
没事啦  明天数美学姐应该也会陪我练习
So I'll take the chance to practice the basic moves several times more.
那样的话  我干脆就加倍练习基本移动好了
Jeez!
真是的
What a nagging husband!
啰里啰嗦的老公
Hey, what do you mean, husband?
等等  什么老公啊
What's up, Sonoko?
怎么了  园子
Sorry! We have guests?
抱歉  有客人吗
Welcome home, Sonoko!
你回来啦  园子
You should knock, first.
真是的  进来也不敲个门
It's okay! It's more important to keep the energy up!
没事没事  充满朝气比什么都好
So she must be your daughter, right?
这位就是令嫒了吧
Yes. She's my second daughter, Sonoko.
是的  这是二女儿园子
It's a pleasure to meet you.
初次见面
I'm sorry about her behavior.
让您见笑了  真是的
She is still lacking in self-awareness as a successor of the Suzuki Group.
看来作为铃木财团继承人的觉悟还是不够啊
Just leave it to my big sister.
那种事交给大姐就行了吧
It's a matter of being prepared.
这是心理准备的问题
Oh, by the way,
啊  对了
the two standing behind my daughter
在园子身后站着的
are her friends, Ran Mouri and Shinichi Kudo.
是她的朋友  毛利兰和工藤新一
Ran-san's father used to be a police officer
小兰的父亲之前是警察
and is now working as a private detective.
现在是个私家侦探
Why don't you consult with him regarding that matter you told me of earlier?
之前那件事  找他商量一下怎么样
Well...
这个嘛
Which matter was that?
之前那件事？
Oh, Sewa-san here is going to hold a party this weekend,
啊  这位濑羽先生这周末打算举办派对
and he came with his wife to invite us to the party.
难得他们夫妇二人特意上门盛情相邀
Unfortunately, I had already
但是我在那天
made plans to take part in a jewel exhibit at the Beika Museum that day,
不巧还有一场关于即将在米花博物馆举办宝石展的会议
so I won't able to go to the party.
所以就无法参加派对了
Ah? You mean the Black Star exhibit that Mr. Jirokichi talked about?
就是次郎吉叔叔说过的那个漆黑之星的宝石展
That's right.
是的
However, Sewa-san just told us
但是  据濑羽先生所言
that they received a threatening letter asking them to cancel their party,
他收到了一封让他取消派对的恐吓信
otherwise, one of the guests would die during the party.
信上写着参加派对的人中有人会丧命
I see.
原来如此
In that case, you should let this Shinichi Kudo-kun to take care of it.
如果是这种事的话  就交给这位工藤新一先生吧
To tell you the truth,
不瞒你们说
Shinichi-kun is a high school student who's solved many difficult cases!
新一可是解决了众多疑难案件的高中生侦探哦
It might be a little offensive to Ran,
虽然这么说有点对不住小兰
but I think he's a better detective than Ran's father.
他应该比小兰家那位爸爸更可靠
If you let me handle this, I think I can help you!
如果您委托我  我应该能帮上您的忙
That's certainly promising.
确实可靠啊
However, we have
啊  不过
taken extra precautions by increasing security and hiring more guards,
以防万一  我已经增加了警备人员
so we won't need to trouble you anymore.
所以就不劳侦探先生费心了
Then we'll be excusing ourselves now.
那么  我们差不多要先行告辞了
Right?
喂
Yes.
是
Dear!
亲爱的
What are you doing?
真是的  你在干什么啊
Can't you be more careful?
给我小心一点啊
Oh... Well...
啊  这个
Thanks to you nothing happened.
托你的福得救了啊
Miss, thank you!
这位小姐  谢谢你
Not at all.
不用谢
Ran's such a good girl!
不愧是小兰
Thank you very much!
非常感谢
You're not injured, are you?
您没受伤吧
I'm fine! I guess I take after my father, having such a strong body!
没事的  我像我爸一样  仅仅是四肢发达而已
You still can't get over what I said? Sorry!
你还在介意我刚才的话吗  对不起
It's not like that! The Mouri family is really amazing!
不是不是  毛利家真的很厉害啊
Come on, Sonoko.
真是的  园子
Kudo-kun.
工藤
Is something wrong?
怎么了吗
No. Nothing.
不  没什么
Wow! This uniform is really nice!
哇  这道服  很棒啊
It's made from an extremely lightweight material that's been newly developed
这可是用我们铃木财团旗下的纤维制造商最新开发的
by our very own Suzuki Group's fabric manufacturer!
超轻材料制成的哦
In addition, we slightly narrowed the sleeves,
而且由于把袖子部分稍微改窄了一点
so it fits better and is easier to move around in.
就更合身更便于活动了
Believe it or not, I'm also a martial arts enthusiast!
别看我这样  我也是个格斗爱好者呢
But is it okay for me to take it?
但是  就这样给我真的没关系吗
Of course!
没事没事
Actually, I took a tiny part in designing it.
实际上  我也稍微参加了一点设计工作
You did?
真的吗
Yes! Call me Lady Sonoko, the charismatic designer!
嗯  请叫我大设计师园子大人
As long as you have this uniform on,
只要穿着这道服
you'll win the championship for sure!
就绝对能拿下冠军
This is the power of love!
这可是爱的力量
Ah, about that...
啊  这个嘛
What's the matter?
怎么了吗
She can't wear this in the match.
那件道服不能用来比赛啊
What? Really?
什么  真的吗
Yes. The match has strict regulations about the uniforms.
对的  每次大赛都会对道服作出规定
I'm sorry, Sonoko. But I'll wear this during practice and do my best!
抱歉了园子  但是我会穿着它努力练习的
Then there's nothing we can do. But in return,
这也是没办法的事嘛  不过相应的
you've got to win the competition, or I won't forgive you!
你要是不拿下冠军  我可不原谅你哦
Ma'am, I'm sorry!
阿姨  对不起
That's quite alright.
没事啦
We can't be there to cheer for you,
我们没办法去现场给你呐喊助威
but we wish you good luck!
加油哦
Thank you!
好的
Turns out we didn't get to buy a new phone.
结果手机也没买成
Yeah.
是啊
I'll go home after picking up some things for dinner.
那我去买了晚餐的食材就回家
Okay. I'll get you a phone some other time.
好  下次再买手机吧
Mmhm. See you!
嗯  回头见
Take care!
路上小心
I left my wallet at your house!
我把钱包忘在新一家了
Gosh!
真是的
Shinichi!
新一
I found my wallet. I'm going home now.
钱包找到了  我回家了哦
Okay.
知道了
Wow, there are so many books here.
话说  这里的书可真多啊
And all of them are mystery novels.
而且还全是推理小说
It must be because your father has read them all
正是因为把这些书全都看完了
that he was able to become a world-famous mystery writer.
新一的爸爸  才能成为世界级推理作家的吧
You, however, only turned into a mystery geek.
而新一却只成了个推理白痴
Will you be quiet?
你很吵啊
And on top of that, your mom is the legendary, beautiful actress,
而且  你妈妈还是那个传说中的美女演员
Yukiko Fujimine.
藤峰有希子啊
I'm so jealous of you!
好羡慕
What's so good about that?
这又不是什么好事
Hey, I bet your first love was your mom, right?
诶  新一的初恋对象肯定是你妈妈吧
No! Not at all!
才  才不是
Then who was it?
那是谁啊
My first love was...
我的初恋对象啊
Who?
她是？
She was...
初恋对象是…
Can't you give me a break, Professor Agasa?
你就适可而止吧  阿笠博士
Hahaha! How's it going?
哈哈哈  如何啊
How's your homework coming along?
作业呢  有进展了吗
I thought it was about the time you got sleepy.
我想你差不多也到了犯困的时候了吧
So, you're wide awake now, aren't you?
怎么样  现在清醒了吧
Ouch!
好痛
Don't move, Professor!
别动  博士
Sorry!
不好意思
So, what were you experimenting with this time?
所以呢  这次又是在做什么实验
So you really are interested after all!
你果然很在意啊
Well, not really.
没有  并不在意
Well, since you've asked, I may as well just tell you.
真是没办法啊  既然你都这么说了那我就告诉你吧
Ta-da!
锵～
It's Personal Mobility Rocket! Ta-da!
单人移动火箭  锵～
Stop saying "Ta-da."
你就别「锵」了
When I complete it, not only will it relieve traffic congestion,
待它完成  不但能解决交通堵塞问题
it'll also make me rich!
还能让我成为大富翁
I can prevent accidents and become rich!
既不会发生事故  我又能当大富翁
Ah... But
啊  但是
it might be worse in that case.
真那样就糟了吧
Isn't it basically a missile?
这是像导弹一样的东西对吧
What are you talking about? My inventions are always the safest!
你在说什么啊  我发明的东西可都是最安全的
What happened just now was just an accident.
刚才那只是个意外
Ah! Whoa! Shinichi!
哇  哇  新一
P-Professor!
博  博士
Hopeless!
没救了
What? You're such a bother! Don't blame me!
什么啊  你很烦啊  别光指责我
I don't wanna go with you, either!
我也不想和你一起去啊
I said yes because Ran asked me to be there!
是小兰的要求我才勉为其难答应的
As a father, being there to support your daughter is your job!
作为她的父亲  去现场给女儿加油是理所应当的吧
What I'm saying is, don't you have
我想说的是  在那之前
something much more important coming up before that?
不是还有更重要的工作要做吗
I bet you haven't got any requests for work this month anyway.
反正你这个月肯定又是什么工作委托都没有
Don't you jump to conclusions like that!
你别随便下定论
I've found three animals this month!
这个月我可找到了3只啊
Three animals?!
3只？
What is that? A well-known private detective is looking for lost dogs?
什么嘛  了不起的私家侦探居然找狗去了啊
Not dogs, but cats!
才不是狗  是猫
Don't underestimate me! The other day...
别小瞧我  最近这几天
-I'm home! -I caught a famous actress having an affair with her producer...
-我回来了 -我可是闯进了著名女演员和制片人的外遇现场
What? It was a case! A big case!
什么  是案件  还是个大案件呢
-You think you are a first-class business consultant? How smug! -I'll call you when dinner is ready, then.
-什么一流企业的顾问  自以为是 -那我做好饭了就叫你哦
You're just only trying to fool us!
只是糊弄我们的吧
But, why did the president
但是  那个社长
pick a place which would draw so much attention
为什么还特意挑那种引人注目的地方
as the site to make the deal?
作为交易场所啊
He probably thinks that we won't dare cause any trouble
大概是自以为只要选在那种地方的话
since it's such a public place.
我们就不敢引起骚动了吧
And even if he brings his people with him,
就算他带了同伙来
they can hide in the crowds.
也能藏身于人群之中
So it's a trap after all.
这果然还是陷阱吧
Bourbon said that the president also had a connection with the Deisankai.
波本说过  那个社长还跟泥参会勾结在一起
Hmph, Bourbon?
哼  波本吗
His nose is as sharp as usual.
那个嗅觉依旧灵敏的家伙啊
Well, even so...
不过  即便如此
We're aware ahead of time, so it should be okay .
我们就算知道这点也没关系
He will be killed eventually anyway.
反正他最后还是会被干掉
(Tokyo Metropolitan Gymnasium   Main arena Inter-High Athletic Competition  Karate Tournament)
-东京体育馆  主竞技场 -高中综合体育大赛  空手道竞技赛
Stop!
停
Awesome!
太好啦
Yeah!
好嘞
Blue, one upper kick!
蓝方  上段踢  一本
Blue won!
蓝方获胜
-Freestyle Karate  Women's group  Semifinal match one  Blue victory -Amazing! That's amazing! Ran's amazing!
-实战对抗 女子组  半决赛第一场蓝方获胜 -好厉害  好厉害  小兰  好厉害
-Freestyle Karate  Women's group  Semifinal match one Blue victory -The final round is coming up, Mr. Mouri!
-下一场就是决赛了  叔叔
Piece of cake!
小菜一碟
After all, Ran inherited the good luck needed to win from me!
毕竟小兰这逢战必胜的运气  可是我这父亲遗传的呀
But you always fail quickly because you get carried away too soon.
但你总是很快就因为得意忘形而马失前蹄
I hope Ran didn't inherit that part from you!
只求这点不要遗传给她
But since Ran is also my daughter, I won't have to worry about that!
不过  既然小兰是我的女儿就应该不用担心
Why, you...
你这个…
Ran! Do your best again in the final!
小兰  决赛也要拿出气势
Speaking of that, where is that guy?
话说回来  这种时候跑到哪里去了  那家伙
Yes! Yes! Understood!
好的  好的  我明白了
I'll be right there, captain!
我马上就过去  警部
The final match of the freestyle karate,
现在  实战对抗  女子组
women's group, will now begin.
决赛即将开始
Red, Hina Wada, from Haido High.
红方  杯户高中  和田阳奈选手
Ready!
是
Blue, Ran Mouri, from Teitan High.
蓝方  帝丹高中  毛利兰选手
Begin!
开始
Yes! Yes! That's it! Keep it up!
好嘞好嘞  保持住啊保持住
Easy does it, Ran!
冷静下来  小兰
Stop!
停
Red, mid-body kick, waza-ari!
红方  中段踢  技有
Continue!
继续  开始
Stop!
停
What are you doing, Ran?
真是的  在干什么啊  小兰
Ran! Keep your spirit up! Spirit!
小兰  气势啊  气势
Fighting spirit! Fight! Fight!
斗志  斗志  来斗志
Ah-haha! Fighting spirit!
啊哈哈  来斗志哟
Calm down.
冷静一点
Shinichi? What's up?
新一  怎么了
A...
案
case...
件
A case?
案件
Every time!
总是这样
It's always case, case, case!
总是这样  案件案件的
You mystery geek!
你这个推理狂
I want you to end this right now!
希望你们适可而止
I don't have time to waste on your fruitless investigations.
我可没时间耗在你们这毫无结果的搜查上
Come on, don't say that.
哎呀  别这么说
I'm sure the culprit of this murder
这起杀人案的犯人
is standing here in the room with us!
一定就在你们这些人之中
In that case, hurry up and point him out!
既然如此  就快点把犯人找出来啊
I already know
我已经知道了
who the murderer is.
犯人到底是谁
Oh! Kudo-kun! You are finally here!
哎呀  工藤老弟  等你好久了
Sorry I'm late.
不好意思  我来晚了
Who is that guy?
是谁啊  那个男人
He looks quite young!
看起来还挺年轻的
You don't remember me? We just met the other day at Suzuki's.
您忘了吗  前几天我们还在铃木家见过面
Huh? At Suzuki's?
嗯？在铃木家
To tell you the truth,
不瞒你们说
Shinichi-kun is a high school student who's solved many tough cases!
新一可是解决了众多疑难案件的高中生侦探哦
That high school detective?
高中生侦探吗
Mr. Yamazaki, the president of Beika Bank,
米花银行行长  山崎先生
was murdered in the guest room of the third-floor in this mansion
在这栋房子3楼的客房里被杀害的时候
right in the middle of the party.
这里刚好是派对最热闹的时候
He was stabbed to death.
死因是被刀刺死
The room door was locked,
房间的门上着锁
and the key was in Mr. Yamazaki's pocket.
门锁的钥匙就放在山崎先生的口袋里
Only the balcony window overlooking the courtyard was open.
房间里只有面向中庭的那扇通往阳台的窗户是开着的
In other words,
也就是说
the murderer snuck in through the balcony window and killed Mr. Yamazaki in his sleep.
犯人是从阳台的窗户闯入客房  将休息中的山崎先生杀害后
And then he fled through the window again.
再从阳台的窗户逃走的
But, there weren't any footprints under the window, were there?
但是  窗户下并没留下足迹吧
Besides, all the rooms around the guest room were locked.
而且这间客房周围的房间都上了锁
It's true. No footprints were found under the window
是的  确实窗户下并没有足迹
and the windows of the surrounding rooms were all locked.
周围的窗户也都锁着
So, how did the murderer get in?
如此一来  到底是怎么办到的
He flew in.
是飞进来的哦
How's that possible?
怎么可能啊
Hold on!
喂喂
W-wait, Kudo-kun!
等等  工藤
I didn't say he flew in from the sky.
当然  我并不是说他是从天上飞进来的
Look, there's a small window on the opposite side of the guest room window.
现场那个窗户的斜对面  有一个小窗户对吧
That's the window where the murderer jumped in through the guest room.
犯人就是从那个小窗户飞跃到客房的窗户这边的
Nonsense!
别胡说了
Those two windows are at least five meters apart!
那两个窗户之间至少有5米的间隔啊
How could one jump that far?
那种事怎么可能做到
Although narrow, there's an overhang
那个小窗户连接着的房顶边缘上
that goes along from the small window to the roof.
实际上有延伸出一小部分落脚处
If one uses that as a foothold and moves along the edge of the wall,
只要踩着那个部分  贴着墙移动的话
it's only one or two meters to the balcony.
和阳台的距离  其实只有1～2米
Therefore, the murderer is one who is intimately familiar with the unique construction of this mansion,
也就是说  犯人是熟知这栋房子的特殊构造的人
and one who could move around
并且  能在那个时间
the mansion at that time without raising anyone's suspicion.
在不被任何人怀疑的情况下  在这家中任意活动的人
So, hurry and spill it!
快  快说啊
Who killed President Yamazaki?
杀了山崎行长的人到底是谁
It was...
那就是
you,
你啊
Yamazaki's best friend, as well as the master of this house,
既是山崎先生的挚友  又是这里的一家之主
Takanori Sewa-san!
濑羽尊德先生
Th-That's preposterous!
你  你别胡说
How could I do that with a leg like this?
我的脚都成这样了  还怎么办到
I've seen through your trick!
那种伎俩我早就看穿了
What are you doing, punk?
你小子想干什么
F-Father?
父  父亲
Master!
老爷
H-Honey, your leg...
老  老公  你的脚
I noticed this when I first met you at Suzuki's.
在铃木家见到你的时候  我就看到了
When your wheelchair went out of control,
为了让失控的轮椅停下
you instinctively used that leg to stop yourself!
你就下意识伸出那只脚当刹车
Your leg actually healed a long time ago, didn't it?
其实  早就痊愈了吧  你的脚
Darn it all!
可恶
Stop!
站  站住
Don't you run away!
休想逃跑
Goal!
命中
Oh, you helped us again, Kudo-kun.
哎呀  又劳你费力啦  工藤老弟
Not a problem.
哪里哪里
If you have any tough cases,
如果还有疑难案件
feel free to call me, Detective Shinichi Kundo!
就尽管找我工藤新一这个名侦探吧
Hey, have you heard?
诶诶  你听说了吗
That high school detective solved another case!
那个高中生侦探又立功了
Yes! He's so amazing!
嗯  好厉害啊
He can, most certainly, be called the savior of the Japanese police.
他才是真正的日本警察的救世主啊
Ow! What did you do that for?
好痛  你干嘛啊
You were grinning and laughing like an idiot.
谁让你像白痴一样嘿嘿傻笑
Ran, are you mad at me or something?
小兰  干嘛生气啊
Not at all.
没有啊
Though my dad is out of business because of your popularity,
新一的活跃导致我爸爸接不到委托了
I'm not upset about that at all.
我才没有因为这件事生气呢
But it's not my fault that your dad
但是  小兰的爸爸没工作
is out of business, it's his lack of skills.
应该跟我没关系  是他自己的能力问题吧
That's why
所以
I said I wasn't upset at all!
我才说我没有生气啊
She's the head of the karate team indeed!
不愧是  空手道部主将
Honestly, even though people keep calling you "famous detective,"
真是的  就算大家都围着你叫你名侦探名侦探的
you are simply a mystery geek after all.
但根本只是个推理狂嘛
But look at all the fan letters I got!
但是你看  这些粉丝信
People admire a mystery geek like me!
大家都很喜欢我这个推理狂哦
Oh, is that so?
哦  这样吗
(To Kudo-kun)
工藤同学 收
Flirting with girls is fine,
你平时对女孩子色眯眯的也就算了
but you need to be serious when you find one you really like.
对待自己真心喜欢的人还是得专情哦
The one I really like, huh?
真心喜欢的人啊
Gosh!
真是的
What is it?
干嘛啊
Why have you been staring at me?
从刚才就一直盯着我的脸看
Uh... Nothing.
啊  没有  没什么
If you are too obsessed with solving cases,
太得意忘形沉迷于案件里的话
you may get yourself in danger one day.
也许不知何时就会遇到危险哦
Maybe.
可能吧
But why a detective?
但是  为什么是侦探呢
If you are fascinated by mystery novels,
那么喜欢推理小说的话
you could easily become a novelist like your dad.
明明像你爸爸一样当个小说家不是也挺好的吗
I don't want to write about detectives.
我并不想把侦探写在笔下
I want to be one!
而是要自己去成为侦探
I wanna be the Sherlock Holmes of the modern day!
成为平成年代的  夏洛克·福尔摩斯
The more tough cases there are, the more exciting it is!
遇到的疑难案件越多  就越感到心潮澎湃
As long as you experience once the thrill and joy when you catch a culprit,
想方设法找出犯人时的那种刺激  那种快感
you will never be able to stop!
只要体验过一次  就再也无法停止了
And that is a detective!
这就是侦探啊
See you!
回头见
Wait, Shinichi!
等等  新一
You didn't forget what we're doing tomorrow, did you?
明天的约定  应该没忘记吧
Tomorrow?
约定？
You promised
我不是说了吗
that if I won the karate tournament,
如果我在都大赛上拿下冠军
you'd take me to Tropical Land!
你就要带我去多罗碧加热带乐园
Eh? Did I say that?
咦  有这回事吗
You did forget!
真是够了
I didn't want to go with you, anyway!
反正我也不是很想跟新一一起去
Why don't you hang out with those fangirls who wrote you all those letters?
你跟写粉丝信给你的女生一起去玩好了
I was kidding! Just kidding!
开玩笑的啦  玩笑
Don't be mad! Of course I remember.
别生气啊  我记得啦
Tomorrow at 10 a.m., Tropical Land.
明天10点  多罗碧加热带乐园
There's no way I'd forget that.
我怎么可能忘啊
It's your treat, too! Don't forget that either!
全部都是新一请客  这点也别忘了哦
In that case, it's a little...
这么说来好像还真是
Hey! Wait a second! Ran!
喂  等等啊  小兰
Are you kidding? It's been so long since we came back last time,
不会吧  明明这么久没回日本了
and we already have to go back before we could see our son?
居然还没见到儿子就要回去了吗
I put a lot of work into this disguise,
难得想让新一大吃一惊的
thinking I could surprise Shinichi.
我还认认真真地做了变装呢
It was such a waste of effort!
这不是白费功夫了嘛
But we came back this time only to get those old materials.
不过  本来这次回日本就只是为了拿旧资料的
You can save these disguises for some other time.
这套变装就留到之后再用吧
Besides, we'd only become a third wheel anyway.
而且  我们貌似还成了电灯泡呢
I want to be a third wheel and bug Shinichi so much!
好想去当电灯泡被新一讨厌啊
Here. You must be thirsty.
给  渴了吧
Thank you!
谢  谢谢
This way! Come on!
这边这边
Hey, where are we going, Shinichi?
喂  到底是要去哪儿啊  新一
Don't ask. Just follow me!
别问了  跟我来就是了
Ten, nine, eight, seven, six,
10  9  8  7  6
five, four, three, two, one,
5  4  3  2  1
Wow!
哇
This is amazing! How wonderful!
好厉害  好厉害  好厉害
You like this kind of things, don't you?
你  喜欢这种感觉吧
Mmhm.
嗯
And, one of the things that are so amazing about Holmes
然后  要说福尔摩斯厉害的地方啊
is when he first met his assistant, Watson, he could tell instantly that he'd been
就是跟助手华生初次见面的时候  仅仅只是握了一下手
to Afghanistan as a military doctor just by shaking his hand.
就看穿他曾经作为军医去过阿富汗了
Just like this.
就像这样
You are a member of a gymnastics team, aren't you?
你是体操部的吧
H-How did you know?
你  你怎么知道
Hey, do you know him?
怎么了  你认识这个人吗
I don't.
不认识
It's her hand.
根据你的手啊
For a girl to have all these blisters on her hands,
因为女人手上长了这么多茧的
she must be someone who has practiced the horizontal bar.
就只有练习过体操单杠项目的人了
But you can get blisters by playing tennis, too.
但是  打网球也会起茧吧
I was just joking. Actually, when the wind
开玩笑的  其实是因为这个人的裙子
blew her skirt up earlier, I saw she has
刚才被风吹起来的时候我看到了
some unique bruises on her thighs that can only be caused
在大腿根部留下的  只有练习高低杠的人才有的
by practicing on the uneven bars.
独特的淤痕
Never neglecting to observe one's surroundings is fundamental for a detective.
无论何时都不能对周围情况疏于观察  这是做侦探的基本要求哦
Don't be so smug!
什么嘛  自以为是
Isn't it cheating if you knew before you shook her hand?
握手之前就知道了  这不是作弊吗
Hey, you!
喂  你
Stop flirting with my friend!
别随便调戏我朋友啊
Ah? He's your friend?
啊  他是你朋友啊
Yes, he is.
嗯  是啊
In that case, you can take our places.
这样的话  我们就调个位置吧
No. It's fine.
不用啦  没事的
We don't want to bother those two.
打扰到那两个人就不太好了
Ran, honestly, since long time ago I've...
小兰  其实我  从很久以前就对你
Shinichi, me, too!
新一  我也是
Shinichi?
新一
Shinichi, hurry up!
新一  快点啦
Hope you had fun!
大家辛苦了
Watch your steps!
当心脚下
Man! That was so scary!
刚才好可怕啊
I wanna do it again!
还想再坐一次
And then, that was when Holmes...
然后啊  那时  福尔摩斯他…
There are still seats available. Please.
还有空位  两位请
Do you know that?
你知道吗
Conan Doyle must have wanted to say that.
柯南·道尔肯定是想这么说
Holmes is...
福尔摩斯那家伙
That's enough! Will you stop talking about Holmes and Conan Doyle?
真是的  别再跟我说什么福尔摩斯  什么柯南·道尔的了
You mystery geek!
你这个推理狂
I've been looking forward to coming here with you, Shinichi.
我其实一直都很期待跟新一你一起来这里的
Why can't you understand my feelings?
为什么你就是体会不到我的心思呢
Ran...
小兰
Well... Actually, I also...
那个  其实我也…
Silly! Why are you getting nervous?
傻瓜啊  你在慌什么啊
I was obviously kidding!
这明摆着就是骗人的嘛
Darn it!
可恶
Ah? Did I really fool you?
啊  你当真啦
You are so easy to trick! I don't think you're detective material!
这种小把戏都能骗到你  可当不了侦探哦
We're ready to go!
发车咯
Have fun!
一路走好
But
但是啊
it's true that I've been looking forward to this!
期待的那份心情  是真的哦
Hmph, what is this? We don't even get a turn?
嘁  什么啊  居然没机会出场
Come on. Off we go.
走吧  回去了
He asked us to leave.
他说撤退
What? You wanna ride that?
干嘛  你想坐啊
What is it? Water?
什么  水吗
It's salty.
咸的
What is this?
什么啊  这是
Huh? What?
什  什么
Hope you had fun!
大家辛苦了
Watch your steps!
当心脚下
An accident!
是事故
Call an ambulance!
快叫救护车
And call the police!
还有警察
Why did Kishida-kun...
为什么  岸田会…
Shinichi.
新一
Hmph. What an unlucky guy!
哼  真是个倒霉鬼
It's an accident anyway.
总之这只是个事故
Just let us leave.
让我们走吧
Hold on!
等等
It's not an accident.
这不是事故
It's a murder.
这是杀人案件
And the murderer is amongst the seven of us who rode
并且犯人就在  和被害者同乘一辆云霄飞车的
the same coaster as the victim.
我们这7人之中
Shinichi.
新一
Hmph! I don't have time for this!
嘁  我们可没空陪你
Excuse us!
不好意思
Coming through! Excuse us!
请让一让  不好意思
Excuse us! Over here.
不好意思  在这边
Oh, Kudo-kun!
啊  工藤老弟
Ah, Ran-kun is also here!
小兰也在啊
Hi, Inspector Megure.
啊  目暮警部
Kudo!
工藤
Oh! So that's the famous high school detective, Shinichi Kudo!
噢  那就是有名的高中生侦探工藤新一吗
The one who's been solving tough cases one after another!
一次次解决了匪夷所思的疑难案件的那位
He's known as the savior of the Japanese police!
日本警察的救世主
Hey, come here! It's Kudo-kun! Kudo-kun!
喂快来快来  是工藤啊工藤
Will you show us what you can do?
就让我们见识一下您的本事吧
Well...
这个
Oh! Come on!
你够了
I see.
原来如此
There's certainly no sign of an accident or malfunction of any kind on the roller coaster.
云霄飞车的器材上的确没有任何事故或者故障的痕迹
And judging from the body, it's highly unlikely that it was a suicide.
从死者的状况来看  自杀的可能性也很小
Yes, Inspector Megure. That's why it's clearly a murder.
是的  目暮警部  如此看来  这很明显是谋杀
But, who killed him, and how?
但是  犯人是谁  又是怎么杀害他的呢
Inspector.
警部
We'll have those who rode with the victim remain here.
请一起乘坐这辆云霄飞车的人留在这里
The rest of you are free to leave.
其他的人就请回吧
It's not an accident?
不是事故
What's going on?
这算什么嘛
Please stand back!
请离开
This coaster has eight seats.
这辆云霄飞车是八人共乘
Assuming you and Ran are innocent, there are five possible suspects.
把你和小兰姑且排除在外的话  嫌疑人共五位
Riding in the first row were the victim's friends A and B.
第一排坐着的是被害者的朋友A和朋友B
Riding next to the victim in the third row
和被害者同坐在第三排的是
was the victim's friend/lover, C.
他的朋友兼恋人C
And lastly, riding behind the victim were the men in black D and E.
然后  坐在被害者后面的是黑衣男D和E
But that being the case, everyone was locked in by the safety guard
但是  这样的话  所有人都有安全杆保护着
and couldn't move,
身体无法移动
which means only the woman sitting next to him could have killed him.
能够实施杀人行动的只有被害者旁边的那位女性了
Wait. It could also be the two men sitting behind him...
啊不  后排的男士也有可能吗
Hey! Hurry up!
喂  快点
We don't have time to play this detective game with you!
我们可没有时间陪你们玩侦探游戏
B-Boss...
大  大哥
Sorry for the inconvenience, but we need you to cooperate.
不好意思  请再配合一会儿
What is that?
怎么回事
This guy has got this murderous look,
这家伙的目光如此冰冷
as if killing people was a game to him!
就好像  杀多少人也不在乎一样
Wh-Who is he?
这  这家伙到底…
Inspector Megure.
目暮警部
Yes? What is it, Chiba-kun?
嗯？  怎么了  千叶
We found this
从这位女士的包里
in this woman's purse.
发现了这样的东西
N-No way! I know nothing about this!
骗  骗人的吧  我不知道有这东西
A-Aiko! Why did you do such a thing?
爱  爱子  你为什么要做那种事
No! It wasn't me!
不  不是的  不是我
I thought you and Kishida-kun were in love! Why?
岸田和你不是很恩爱吗  为什么
You have to believe me! It wasn't me!
相信我  不是我做的
Alright! You've found the murderer!
好了  犯人就是那娘们了
Hurry and let us leave, detective!
快点让我们回去吧  警官
Finding the killer was a lot easier than I thought it'd be.
找犯人比预想的要简单得多啊
I also think that woman is suspicious.
我也觉得那女人可疑呢
Is it because they had a fight?
是恋人之间吵架的原因吗
Women are horrible!
女人好恐怖
Okay. Take that woman in as our prime suspect!
好  将那位女士作为嫌疑人带走
Now, come with us.
那么  请到这边来
Th-This can't be...
不  不是吧…
And as a precaution,
接下来  为了以防万一
we'll also need to confirm the identities of the other riders.
同乘云霄飞车的其他人也要确认一下身份
It's not a problem, is it?
没有问题吧
Hold on, Inspector!
等等  警部
Eh? What's wrong, Kudo-kun?
嗯  怎么了  工藤老弟
You've got the wrong suspect.
犯人不是这位女士
S-Shinichi?
新  新一
Kudo-kun.
工藤老弟
The one who murdered
在这辆云霄飞车上
Kishida-san on the roller coaster
杀害被害者岸田先生的犯人
is you!
就是你！
W-What?
什  什么
What are you talking about?
你在说什么啊
You saw the murder weapon in Aoko's purse!
你们也都看到了从爱子的包里找到的作案用刀具
A knife like that can't sever a human's neck at all,
那种东西根本砍不下人的头颅
much less with a woman's strength.
更何况还是以女性的力量
Besides, if she were the killer,
而且  如果她是犯人的话
she would've had plenty of chances to get rid of the weapon.
应该有很多扔掉凶器的机会
Why would she wrap it up with a piece of cloth and hide it in her purse?
没必要特意用布包好藏在包里
It's because you framed Aiko-san!
那是因为你要嫁祸给爱子小姐
You put the knife in her purse beforehand, didn't you?
预先放在她的包里的  不是吗
Stop talking nonsense!
别说蠢话了
My seat was separated by another row from Kishida-kun's!
我的座位是在已死的岸田的前面的前面
How could I manage to cut off his head?
那我是如何砍下岸田的头颅的？
And you just said it yourself
而且  你刚才不是说过吗
that it can't be done with a woman's strength!
以女性的力量是砍不下来的
It's true that a woman alone can't do it.
的确  只以女性的力量无法做到
But, when you factor in the speed of the coaster
但是  利用云霄飞车的速度
and the use of piano wire or steal rope, it's certainly possible.
以及钢琴线或者钢圈就有可能了
Inspector Megure, I need all the officers to do me a favor.
目暮警部  让警察先生们帮帮忙可以吗
I want to reenact the crime.
我想再现案发经过
Oh, of course!
啊  这个没有问题
Are you ready, guys?
准备好了吗  大家
I'm playing the suspect, Hitomi-san.
我是犯人  也就是小瞳小姐的角色
And Inspector Megure is playing the victim, Kishida-san.
目暮警部演被害者岸田先生的角色
First, before lowering the safety guard,
首先  在安全杆降下之前
you put a bag or something between your back and the back of the seat,
把背包之类的东西夹在后背和座椅靠背之间
then lowered the guard.
放下安全杆
And before the crime, you removed the bag and freed yourself from the gap.
然后在实施谋杀前  取出夹在背后的背包  从缝隙中挣脱出来
See? It's easy to get out.
看  很简单就能脱身了
Next, you pulled out a tool such as a piano wire or steel rope
接下来  取出预先准备好的工具
that had a hook-like apparatus attached,
即钢琴线或者钢圈和钩子连在一起的工具
and climbed on the safety guard
再把脚卡在安全杆上
and reached back
身体向后延伸
to place the noose around the victim's neck.
把作案工具挂在被害者的脖子上
All of this happened in the pitch-black tunnel, of course.
当然  是在一片黑暗的隧道中进行
And finally, you toss the hook attached to the rope and hooked it onto the coaster's rails.
完成之后再把铁圈另一端系着的钩子勾在云霄飞车的轨道上
Then you could just let the speed and pulling power of the coaster
就可以利用云霄飞车的速度和力量
take care of the rest and rip through the victim's neck!
将被害者的头颅割下
Th-That's nonsense!
胡  胡说八道
Like I could do that on a fast-moving coaster!
在行进中的云霄飞车上怎么可能做到
But, you are a gymnast.
不  你是练体操的
The other girls may not be able to do it,
先不论其他的女性如何
but you, as one who's been trained in your sense of balance,
如果是锻炼过平衡感的你
can surely complete those moves on a coaster.
在云霄飞车上能够做到这种程度的动作
Hey!
等等
Will you knock this o...
你适可而止吧
What happened to your necklace-
你的项链去哪了
the pearl necklace you had
乘坐云霄飞车之前
around your neck before getting
还戴在你脖子上的
on the coaster?
珍珠项链
You swapped out the thread in your necklace for piano wire
你把项链的链子换成了钢琴线
and had the hook attached to it hidden in your purse.
并把连着钢琴线的钩子藏在了那个包里
Wait a second!
等一下
If that's what happened,
如果是用你刚才说的方法
the two sitting behind Kishida-kun
坐在岸田后面的两个人
could also easily do that!
也能很容易做到不是吗
No. Though they appear to be suspicious,
不  虽然他们一看就很可疑
they didn't kill him.
但不是犯人
How do you know?
为什么
I don't know why they'd ride the roller coaster,
我不知道他们乘坐云霄飞车是有什么目的
and they've been anxious to leave since the police got here.
虽然他们在警察来的那一刻  仿佛想赶快从这里离开
Their sudden change of attitude is quite suspicious.
态度突然转变是很可疑
But if they were the killers, they should've seen this coming.
但如果是犯人的话  应该能预见到警察会来这种事
That's right. The killer knew that the victim was going to die,
是的  犯人很清楚  被害者会死
so she cried.
所以流泪了
What is it? Water?
什么  水吗
It didn't take much time for the coaster to reach the terminal from the moment
出了隧道  知道被害者死了  到停在这里
we got out of the tunnel and found out the death of the victim.
根本没有多少时间
So, no one except the killer would shed a long trail of tears
也就是说  乘坐云霄飞车时就流下大滴泪水的
while riding the coaster.
除了犯人以外没有别人了
Then did you see Hitomi crying on the coaster?
那么  你看到小瞳在云霄飞车上哭了吗
Can you prove that?
你能证明吗
The traces of her tears are hard evidence!
她的泪痕就是证据
Only when riding a coaster
只有在乘坐云霄飞车时
can one's tears flow horizontally!
眼泪才会横流
It's... It's all...
一  一切
It's all his fault!
一切都是那个人的错
Because he dumped me!
那个人把我抛弃了
H-Hitomi, you and Kishida-kun dated each other before?
小  小瞳  难道你和岸田交往过
Yes!
是啊
We fell in love long before we met
在进入大学认识你们的很久之前
all of you in college!
我们就相爱着
But, it was ruined by Aiko...
可是  却被爱子…
that woman...
被那个女人
That's why... That's why...
所以  所以…
I decided to use the necklace he gave to me to kill him on the roller coaster
我要在和那个人最初约会的云霄飞车上
which we rode on our first date,
用他送给我的项链杀了他
and
然后
to pin the crime on Aiko!
嫁祸给爱子
Later, a large quantity of sleeping pills was found in her purse.
这之后  从她的背包里发现了大量的安眠药
Apparently she wanted to commit suicide after killing Kishida-san.
看来是想在作案后追随岸田先生的脚步而自尽
Two hours later, the necklace used as a murder weapon was located in the tunnel.
两小时后  在隧道中发现了作为作案工具的项链
The thread, as I thought, was swapped out for piano wire.
项链的链子果然换成了钢琴线
The pearls scattered everywhere.
珍珠四散
The few still left on the thread basked in the setting sun, giving off a faint glow,
残留的几颗被夕阳照耀着  散发着惨淡的光芒
almost as if they were huge teardrops.
就好像是大颗的眼泪一般
Come on. Stop crying.
好了好了  别哭了
You sure can stay calm!
你还真是平静
I'm used to a crime scene like that.
我呀  常在现场  都看习惯了
Once, I even saw a dismembered body.
还看过被分尸的呢
That's horrible!
真差劲
Well, it's best to get it out of your mind.
哎呀  快点忘了比较好哦
Because this kind of thing happens all the time.
因为这是经常会发生的事啦
It does not!
才没有呢
That guy!
那个男子
One of the suspicious men who just rode the coaster!
是刚才乘坐云霄飞车的可疑家伙
You are the one who told me that nothing would happen at an amusement park...
是你说的  如果是游乐园就不会发生案件了
I'm sorry, Ran, just go home without me.
不好意思  小兰  你先回去吧
I'll catch up with you in a bit!
我马上就会追上你的
Shinichi!
新一
He's gone!
已经不见了
Somehow, I had a horrible feeling at that moment
那个时候  不知道为什么我有一种预感
that I might never see Shinichi again...
从此之后我再也见不到新一的不祥的预感
Damn... I lost him!
可恶  跟丢了
Sorry for the wait, Mr. President.
久等了  社长先生
There he is!
在这
A-As promised, I came here alone.
我  我遵守约定  是一个人来的
Yeah. I know you came here alone.
知道  我知道你是一个人来的
I confirmed it from the rollercoaster.
在云霄飞车上已经确认过了
Hurry up and give it to me!
快  快点把那个东西给我
What's the rush? Show me the money first.
别着急  把钱先拿来
Here! Will this shut you up?
给你  别废话了
Wow! That could easily be a hundred million Yen!
天哪  有一个亿吧
Good! Deal accepted.
好  交易成立
Now, give me the film!
那么  快点把胶片给我
Film?
胶片
Here!
给
Those are all the photos and recordings that could be taken as evidence of your company smuggling weapons.
这就是作为你公司走私枪支证据的照片和底片
I suggest you quit that bad business.
别做坏事啦
Shut it! It's nothing compared to what your organization is doing!
闭嘴吧  和你们组织做的事相比  我这又算得了什么
Hey! Exactly what do you know about us?
喂  你到底对我们知道多少  啊？
Ah... Nothing!
啊  不
I've made it clear that the one hundred million you've paid is for your own life.
都说了只要1亿就可以饶你不死
If you get that, you should shut down your company and disappear immediately!
明白了的话  就赶紧关了公司跑路吧
We are going to build a new lab on that piece of land!
我们还想在那片地上建新的实验室呢
Okay!
是
Oh, man! Seriously?
喂喂  真的假的
The detective game is over!
侦探游戏到此为止了
Boss!
大  大哥
You idiot! You were followed by this kid!
蠢货  竟然会被这种小鬼跟踪
Isn't he the detective from earlier?
这小鬼不是刚才的侦探吗
Damn! Let's kill him!
可恶  把他做掉吧
Wait!
等一下
With that death that just happened, the cops should still be around.
经过刚才一闹  条子应该还在附近晃悠
Then what should we do?
那怎么办
Use this.
用这个
This is the poison newly developed by our organization.
组织新开发的毒药
It leaves no traces that can be detected in the body,
吃下这种毒药之后无法从尸体上检出任何毒素
making a perfect crime possible.
可以达成完全犯罪
Although, it's only a prototype drug yet to be tested on humans.
不过这是还没有进行过人体实验的试验品
Boss, we have to go now!
快走吧  大哥
Okay.
嗯
So long, famous detective.
再见了  名侦探
Damn! My body's burning up!
可恶  身体好热
If feels like my bones are melting!
骨头  骨头好像要融化一样
Damn it! I'm dying!
可恶  不行了
Hey! Get over here!
喂  快来个人
It's a dead body!
有人死了
What?
什么
Am I really dead?
我果然已经死了吗
No! He's still breathing!
不  还有呼吸
Hurry! Call an ambulance!
救护车  快叫救护车
I'm alive?
还活着？
I see! That drug must not work on humans!
对了  一定是那种药对人体没有作用
Lucky me!
太幸运了
How awful! His head is bleeding!
好严重啊  头都流血了
The police?
警察吗
So many of them!
来了好多啊
Alright! I'll tell the cops what happened!
这样的话  就把那些人的事全部告诉他们吧
Hey! Hang in there!
喂  振作一点
Can you stand up,
站得起来吗
little boy?
小朋友
Huh?
诶
Are you okay, little boy?
没事吧  小朋友
Little boy?
小朋友？
What is he talking about?
这些人在说什么
I'm a second-year high schooler!
我可是高中二年级的学生了
How did you get the wound on your head?
你头上的伤是怎么回事
Wound? Oh, right!
伤？  对了
I was hit from behind by that man in black.
那个时候  我被黑衣男子从身后打了一棒
Ow!
疼
Huh?
诶
Wh-What happened to my clothes?
怎  怎么回事  这件衣服
You must be scared, little boy.
你一定很害怕吧  小朋友
But we are here now. So, don't worry!
但是  叔叔们已经来了  你就放心好了
Th-This man lifted me up with such ease...
这  这家伙竟然能这么轻松地就把我举起来
Yes. We found a young boy with cranial injuries near the ferris wheel and we've taken him into our care.
没错  在摩天轮下发现了一个头部受伤的少年并已经保护起来了
We'll send him to the medical room now.
现在准备送去医务室
He looks about six or seven years old. I think he's an elementary schooler.
年龄在六七岁左右  看起来是小学生的样子
An elementary schooler? Who?
小学生  在说谁啊
I'm home.
我回来了
Oh! Ran, you're back!
你回来了啊  小兰
Come on, dad! You made a mess again!
爸爸  你真是的  又乱成这样
That's why you don't have any clients,
就是因为这样才会没有委托工作上门啊
and why my mom ran out on you!
妈妈也离家出走了
Stop it! I'm just being selective!
啰嗦  我是在挑委托接
Speaking of that, where's that high school detective guy?
话说回来  那个自称侦探的小鬼怎么了
Weren't you with him today?
今天你们不是在一起的吗
I'll catch up with you in a bit!
我马上就会追上你的
What happened exactly, Shinichi?
到底怎么了啊  新一
Haha! You had a fight, didn't you?
哈哈  看起来是吵架了吧
Well, just get over him!
啊  让他去吧  让他去吧
Detectives are usually bad people anyway!
反正当侦探的都不会是什么正经人
But you're also a detective, dad.
爸爸你不也是侦探吗
I've told you that.
所以刚才不是说了吗
I saw them!
我刚刚看见了
A weapons smuggler and a blackmailer!
走私枪支的人  和以此为由勒索他的人
But the blackmailer's partner found me.
但是被另外一个同伙发现
He attacked me from behind and wounded my head.
被从背后偷袭  击中头部
Hey, little boy.
喂  小朋友
You watch too many police dramas.
是不是刑侦电视剧看太多了
I'm not a little boy! I'm an 11th grader!
我才不是小孩  我已经高二了
So strange.
好奇怪啊
What happened to me?
怎么了
We just checked, but no one called in for a missing child.
经过刚才的确认  没有符合条件的儿童走失报案
Those people's reactions...
这些家伙的反应
These baggy clothes...
松松垮垮的衣服
And...
然后
my voice...
我的这种声音
Damn! How could it be possible?
可恶  怎么可能会有这样的事情
No! No matter how impossible it seems,
不  就算有多么难以置信
only one truth will...
真相永远只有…
What's going on?
怎么回事
It can't be! My body has actually shrunk!
骗人的吧  我的身体竟然真的变小了
Like I said, he doesn't want to go home, and he's been telling wild stories.
都说了他不愿意回家  一个劲地说些不着边际的话
In that case, it's highly possible that he ran away from home.
这样的话  果然很有可能是离家出走啊
Anyway, let's report this to HQ first.
总之先和总部联络一下吧
We'll have to send him to the police child care center.
看来只能放在警察的托管所了
C-Child care center?
托  托管所
Okay, little boy, we...
那  小朋友  我们…
H-He's gone!
消  消失了
The window! He escaped through the window!
是窗户  从窗户逃走了
You've got to be kidding me!
开什么玩笑
Like I'd let you put me in a place like that!
怎么能被带去那种地方
Hey! Little boy!
喂  小朋友
It's huge!
好高
There he is! This way!
发现了  在这里
Damn!
可恶
Stop running, little boy!
别跑啊  小朋友
Jeez! I'm not a criminal, okay?
真是的  我是罪犯吗
Hey, little boy!
喂  小朋友
Hey!
喂
Hey! Did you see him?
喂  这边怎么样？
Ran!
小兰
Great! If I have Ran come here and pick me up...
太好了  这样让小兰来接我的话
But with my current voice
但是以我现在的这种声音
and this body...
再加上这个身体
Damn!
可恶
Got it! At least I can text her!
对了  至少发条短信
But who would believe an uncanny thing like this?
不行  这种事说出去也没人会信
If you are too obsessed with solving cases,
太得意忘形沉迷于案件里的话
you may get yourself in danger one day.
也许不知何时就会遇到危险哦
Go search over there!
那边也好好找找
Damn it! Damn it! Damn it!
可恶  可恶  可恶
"Hi, this is Kudo.
你好  我是工藤
I'm not available at the moment.
现在正外出办事
please leave a message after the beep."
有事请在听到提示音后留言
He's not home, either.
他也没有回家
I bet he's having dinner with his father, that famous novelist!
多半是和他那个了不起的小说家爸爸出去吃晚饭了吧
What are you talking about? Shinichi's parents relocated in the U.S. three years ago.
你在说什么啊  新一的父母三年前就去美国定居了
Shinichi lives by himself.
现在新一是自己一个人生活的啊
Oh. I see.
啊  是这样啊
Something must have happened to him!
果然那之后发生了什么事吧
I'm going to Shinichi's!
我还是去一趟新一家吧
Hey!
什么
What about my dinner?
那我的晚饭怎么办
A short run already has me
只是跑了这么一点路
panting like this!
就喘成这样
And what on earth
还有这个身体
happened to my body?
我到底是怎么了
Wait! I remember after
等一下  我记得当时
he attacked me...
被他们打了之后
This is the poison newly developed by our organization.
用组织新开发的毒药
Although, it's only a prototype drug yet to be tested on humans.
不过这是还没有进行过人体实验的试验品
Is it because I took that drug?
难道是因为吃了那种药
Seriously?
不会吧
Are you stupid, standing in the middle of the road like that?
笨蛋  不要在路中间乱晃啊
Watch out, you damn kid!
小心点啊  你这个臭小鬼
Damn kid!
小鬼
How embarrassing!
真丢人
Shoot!
可恶
Shoot! I can't even get into my own house?
可恶  我连自己家也进不去了吗
I can't do anything like this, can I?
这样的话  不是什么也做不了了吗
Oh, no! This is bad!
可恶  麻烦了
Professor Agasa!
阿笠博士
Who are you?
你是谁啊
It's me! Shinichi!
是我  新一啊
What? So you are a child relative of Shinichi's?
什么啊  原来是新一家亲戚的孩子啊
You know, you look just like Shinichi when he was your age!
话说和小时候的新一真像啊
No! I am Shinichi!
不是  我是新一啊
Shinichi Kudo, the 11th grader at Teitan High School!
帝丹高中二年级的工藤新一啊
Hey, Shinichi! You've got a visitor!
喂  新一  你家来客人了
Argh! You still don't believe me!
还是没有相信啊
Ouch!
啊  好痛
Hey, are you okay?
喂  你没事吧
Now, here's what I know about you!
那我把博士的事情说出来吧
Professor Agasa, 52 years old,
阿笠博士  52岁
an eccentric inventor who lives next door.
住在我家隔壁的奇怪发明家
You may call yourself a genius,
虽然自称是天才
but you've invented nothing but junk!
但是发明的东西却几乎都是破烂
Even worse, you have a mole on your butt with a hair growing out of it.
不仅如此屁股上的痣上还有一根毛
My butt...
屁股上…
No one but Shinichi knows that secret of mine!
这  这件事除了新一之外应该没有人知道
I can't believe
没想到新一那家伙
he told my secret to you!
竟然把我的秘密说出去了
That's not it! I am Shinichi!
不是这样的  我就是新一啊
I was drugged and my body shrank!
被灌了奇怪的药  身体变小了
What? Drugged? Shrank?
什么  吃了药  身体变小了
Yes.
是啊
A drug?
药
If there's such a drug,
哼  要是有那样的药
I'd love to see it for myself!
我倒是想亲眼见见
Come with me, you little liar!
过来  可疑的小鬼
I'll take you to the police!
我这就带你去找警察
Then... Then how about this?
那  那这样的话如何
Professor, you just got back from Columbo restaurant, right?
博士  你是刚从哥伦布餐厅回来的对吧
And in quite a hurry.
而且是急急忙忙地
How... How did you know that?
你  你怎么知道
Your clothes, Professor. The front is all wet,
是博士的衣服  虽然前面有湿了的痕迹
but not the back.
但是后面并没有
Because you ran back in the rain.
这就是在雨中跑步的证据
In addition, you have mud splashed on your pants.
再加上裤子上沾了泥巴
What?
什么
The only muddy road in this neighborhood
这附近会沾上泥巴的路
is front of Columbo restaurant, which is under construction.
就只有正在施工的哥伦布餐厅的前面
Furthermore, you have the distinctive color of Columbo's specialty meat sauce on your mustache.
而且胡子上还沾着颜色特殊的哥伦布特制肉酱汁
So...you are really...
这  这么说来  你真的是
It's only an initial judgment, Mr. Agasa!
这只是初步的判断哟  阿笠先生
S-Shinichi?
新  新一
Are you really Shinichi?
难道  你真的是新一
Haven't I told you so? I was drugged and my body shrank!
所以刚才不是说过了吗  我被灌了药  身体变小了
It's still hard to believe!
还是难以置信
Scientifically speaking, such thing is impossible...
从科学上来说  不可能会发生这种事
But since you were right about my butt...
但是  刚才说的屁股
Anyway, let me get inside first!
总之先让我回家吧
What? A weapons smuggler?
什么  你说枪支走私
Yeah.
是啊
And then I saw a guy was blackmailing him.
然后我看到有人以此为由进行勒索
So they drugged you to keep your mouth shut?
所以他们为了封口  给你灌了毒药？
I see.
这样啊
So basically, a strange side effect of the incomplete drug
在还未完成的药所产生的不可思议的作用下
made your body shrink!
身体变小了
Pretty much!
就是这样
Professor, please! You are a genius, right?
喂  拜托啦  博士你不是天才吗
Could you make a drug to turn me back to normal?
做一个能让我身体恢复原状的药吧
Don't be absurd!
别强人所难了
I know nothing about the composition of that drug...
我对那个药的成分都一无所知
Oh, boy! My childhood clothes fit me perfectly!
真是的  小时候的衣服竟然刚好合身
Then I'll just need to track down their whereabouts
那样的话  查出那帮家伙的所在地
and get a sample of that drug.
拿到那种药的话
Yes. If we had that drug, I might be able to do something with it.
是啊  如果有那种药的话或许能做些什么
But, Shinichi, you can't tell anyone else about your accident!
新一  你的身体变小了这件事除了我以外可对谁都不能说啊
Eh? Why?
诶 为什么
If they find out
如果你还活着
you are still alive and you are Shinichi Kudo,
你就是工藤新一的事情被他们知道的话
they'll surely come for you again.
肯定还会被那帮家伙盯上的
In that case, it'll put those around you in danger, as well.
而且  还会危及你周围的人
Remember, the fact that you are Shinichi Kudo
听好了  你的真实身份是工藤新一的事
is a secret between only you and me!
只能是你和我两个人之间的秘密
No one else can know about this!
绝对不能告诉任何人
Not even Ran-kun, of course!
当然  就算是小兰也是
Okay. I got it!
好了  我知道了啦
Shinichi! Are you home?
新一  你在吗
Jeez! If you are home, at least pick up the phone!
真是的  回来了的话至少接下电话啊
And you didn't even lock your door!
你门都没锁
It... It's Ran!
是  是小兰
Oh, no! Go hide!
不好  赶快藏起来
Hide... Where?
藏  藏在哪里啊
Oh! Professor Agasa?
阿笠博士
Ah! Long time no see, Ran!
啊  真是好久不见啊  小兰
Where's Shinichi?
新一呢
Well...he was just here.
不  那个  刚才在这里的
Well...
这个…
-My father's glasses! It could be a disguise. -He rushed out for a case.
-爸爸的眼镜  伪装一下 -因为突然有了案件  急急忙忙地出门了
Who's this boy?
这孩子是谁呀
Well...this kid...
啊  不  这孩子是
What a shy boy!
真是个害羞的孩子呀
Hey, turn around!
喂  转过来嘛
This is bad...
不  不好
Th-This kid...
这  这孩子
Crap!
完了
You're so cute!
好可爱呀
Her chest!
胸部
Professor, who is this boy?
博士  这个孩子是谁啊
Well, he's the child of a distant relative of mine.
诶  那个  是我远房亲戚的孩子啦
How old are you?
你几岁了呀
16... Oh, no! 6!
16…不是  6岁
Oh, so you are a first grader!
诶  小学一年级吗
Mmm!
嗯  嗯
What's your name?
你叫什么名字
My name is Shin... No...
我  我叫新…不是
Um...
这个
Well, my name is...
这个   我叫…
Conan!
柯南
Eh?
诶
My name is Conan Edogawa!
我叫江户川柯南
Crap! It just slipped right out of my mouth!
完了  一不小心就说出去了
Conan? What an unusual name!
柯南  好奇怪的名字呢
B-Because my father is a big fan of Conan Doyle, so...
因  因为我父亲是柯南·道尔的粉丝  所以…
He looks a little like Shinichi.
和新一有点像啊
Doyle would work...
道尔也不是不可以
Professor.
博士
But why Conan? You're not a foreigner!
什么柯南啊  又不是外国人
She caught me off guard!
那也是没有办法啊
I couldn't think of anything else!
一时间想不出其他的了
Oh, right! Ran,
对  对了   小兰
could you help me babysit him at your house for a while?
不好意思  能不能让这个孩子暂时住在你家
Huh?
诶
You've got to be kiddi...
开什么玩笑
His parents had an accident and were hospitalized.
这孩子的父母因为事故住院了
Though they asked me to watch over him,
虽然被拜托的是我
I'm just a man living by myself...
可我毕竟是个单身汉
Well, I think it's fine, but I have to ask my dad.
嗯  可以是可以  不过得先和我爸爸商量一下
Really?
是吗是吗
So you agree!
那你是接受了
Ow!
好疼
You want me to stay with Ran? What if she finds out who I really am?
住在小兰家的话  我的真实身份暴露了怎么办
Okay, listen.
好了  你听着
Those men will sooner or later find out that you are not dead.
你的尸体没有被发现这件事  很快那帮家伙也会知道
And when that happens, they'll first suspect the people who have access to this house!
到了那时候  进出这间宅子的人会最先被怀疑
Then why can't I stay with you?
那博士家不是也可以
If you wanna get back to normal,
你要恢复成原来的身体的话
you'll have to find the men who drugged you, right?
首先要找到使用那种药的那些家伙不是吗
Well, that's true...
话是这么说没错
Ran's family runs a detective agency.
小兰家可是侦探事务所
Oh, right! They might get some information!
对啊  说不定能得到那些家伙的情报
There you go!
没错
Excuse me, Professor.
等下啊  博士
Yay! I wanna go home with you!
嗯  我想去姐姐家
He's so cute!
好可爱
Professor, please have Shinichi call me when he comes back home.
那博士  等新一回家了你告诉他跟我联系一下
Okay, I will.
好的  我知道了
Bye, uncle! Bye-bye!
再见啦  叔叔   拜拜
See you, Conan-kun!
再见  柯  柯南
It's all up to you now, Shinichi.
接下来就看你的咯  新一
Oh, no! Conan Edogawa-kun.
啊不  江户川柯南
Hey, Conan-kun.
我说  柯南
Conan-kun?
柯南
What's up, Ran-neechan?
啊  怎么了  小兰姐姐
I'm really not used to this name!
真不习惯这个名字
Do you have someone you like?
柯南你有喜欢的人吗
Eh?
诶
I mean, is there someone at school you are fond of?
就是  你在学校里有没有喜欢的人啊
No. Not really.
没有啊  喜欢的人
I have one.
我有哦
And I like him a lot.
非常喜欢的人
Well, by any chance
诶  难不成是
is it that guy called Shinichi you were looking for?
刚刚你在找的那个叫新一的哥哥吗
Correct!
没错
He's always been naughty,
他从小就很顽皮
full of himself and a big mystery geek,
永远充满自信  还是个推理狂
but he can be very dependable, brave and cool
但在关键的时候他却很可靠  勇气十足
at critical moments.
变得特别酷
I really like Shinichi!
我真的好喜欢新一
You need to keep it a secret, though!
但是这不能告诉新一哦
Okay!
嗯    嗯
I've only told this to you, Conan!
这只能告诉柯南哦
You can't tell Shinichi. Got it?
真的不能告诉新一哦
Okay!
嗯    嗯
This is my home.
这里就是我的家了
It feels like I suddenly have a cute younger brother,
总觉得  像是多了个可爱的弟弟似的
to whom I can tell everything!
感觉什么事都可以和你说
Ran...
小兰
I think my dad is home. Let me introduce him to you.
我爸爸好像在家  向你介绍一下  来吧
Wait! Ran...
那个  小兰
Huh?
嗯？
Actually, I...
其实我…
What is it?
什么
I'm actually...
我其实是
Fantastic!
太棒了
What's the matter, dad?
怎么了啊  爸爸
It's here! It's here! It's here!
来了  来了  来了
A job! I've finally got a request in six months!
工作  半年来终于有正经的工作了
Hey! It's dangerous! What is the request?
真是的  很危险诶  你说什么工作啊
A rich family's daughter was kidnapped
有钱人家的大小姐被绑架了
by some men in black!
犯人是黑衣男子
Men in black?
黑衣男子
Conan-kun!
柯南
Just you wait and see, you men in black!
等着吧  黑衣男子
Once I've tracked down your whereabouts
找到你们的所在地
and got a sample of that drug, I can change my body back
把那种药拿到手  然后恢复成原来的样子
and I'll expose all your evildoings!
再把你们干的事全部曝光出来
Thus, in order to obtain information on the men in black,
就这样我为了收集黑衣男子们的情报
I came to stay with Ran, whose father worked as a detective.
住进了父亲是侦探的小兰家中
But her father turned out to be a terrible detective.
但是这个大叔  真是个糊涂到家的侦探
Unable to stand it, I started impersonating her father
实在看不下去的我  借着大叔的身份
and managed to solve tough cases one after another with the help of my natural
用得意的推理能力和阿笠博士发明的道具
deductive reasoning and the gadgets Professor Agasa invented.
一次又一次地解决了各种疑难案件
I didn't expect that Narumi-sensei planned on dying from the very beginning...
没想到成实医生一开始就打算自杀
Narumi-sensei!
成实先生
No, Conan-kun!
不行  柯南
Let me go, Ran-neechan!
放开我  小兰姐姐
What's that sound?
什么  那个声音
It's the code.
是暗号
He's playing it in the flames.
是那个人在火中弹奏的
You idiot!
笨蛋
There's no winning or losing
推理才没有胜负之说
when it comes to deduction!
也没有高低之分
Because only one truth will prevail!
因为真相永远就只有一个
Hey, Hattori.
喂  我说服部你啊
Have you ever killed someone?
有杀过人吗
You idiot...
笨蛋
A detective who corners a murderer
用推理把犯人逼到死角
with their deductions and watches him commit suicide
眼睁睁看着他自杀的侦探
is no different from that murderer.
和杀人犯有什么区别
Hattori, when you have ruled out the impossible,
服部  把不可能的东西全部排除在外
whatever remains, however improbable,
剩下的就算你不相信
must be the truth.
那也是真相
I told you this would be your last chance!
不是说了吗  这是最后的机会
Masami-san!
雅美小姐
Ran-neechan, hurry and call an ambulance!
小兰姐姐  快叫救护车
And inform uncle and the others!
还有通知叔叔他们
Alright!
知道了
It doesn't matter.
没用的
It's too late.
已经太迟了
Don't talk. If you do, your wound will...
不要说话  说话的话伤口会…
Little boy...
小朋友
you are with that detective agency, right?
你是侦探事务所的那孩子对吧
"Organization"?
「组织」
Yes. It's a large, mysterious organization.
是的  被重重谜团包围的巨大组织
As one who's at the lowest rank, all I know is
在最底层的我所能知道的
that the color of the organization is black. That's it.
「组织」的颜色是黑色  仅此而已
Black...
黑色
That's right.
就是这样
Those in the organization prefer wearing clothes as black as crows.
「组织」的那些家伙喜欢穿一身如乌鸦般漆黑的衣服
Could it be?
不会吧
The men in black?
黑衣男子
I'll leave the rest to you...
那就拜托你咯
Little...detective.
小小的侦探先生
He's been given all kinds of names,
形容他的词有很多
such as the Modern-Day Lupin, or the Moonlight Magician.
平成年代的鲁邦  月下的魔术师等等
But there's one that's better-known than the rest.
但其中有一个最广为人知的名字
Better-known?
通称
Because he leads the police of many nations by the nose, as though playing games.
将各国警察像小孩子一样玩于股掌之上
A certain young novelist with an interest in Kaitou No. 1412
对怪盗1412号感兴趣的年轻小说家
looked at the number and read it like this,
看着号码1412  这样读到
"K I D."
「K  I  D.」
K I D?
K  I  D
Wait... So...
喂  那不是
That's right!
对
Kaitou No. 1412.
怪盗1412号
People call him
人称
Kaitou Kid!
怪盗基德
Seems like you are no ordinary kid, boy.
小朋友  你不是普通的小鬼吧
Conan Edogawa, a detective.
江户川柯南  是一个侦探
Yes. That's right.
是  没错
I'm on my way to the shoot location for the drama.
现在正在前往电视剧的外景拍摄现场
It's a wrap once we are done shooting this scene.
这个拍完就杀青了
And then I can go find you.
就能到你那边去了
My job is to help Pisco out and to make sure he won't fail, right?
去帮皮斯克让他不失手就行了是吧
I have something to do there, anyway.
正好去你那边有事
And I want to meet him, too!
也想见见他
I'm hanging up now.
那我挂咯
I gotta lose the FBI's kitty.
我还得甩掉「FBI」的小猫呢
Let's meet there, Gin.
在那见吧  琴酒
Shoot! Move it!
可恶  让开
Out of my way!
把路让开
Move it!
快让开
It's no use.
没用的
But, Shuu...
但  但是  秀
You can never catch up to her with your driving skills.
以你的驾驶技术是追不上她的
But don't worry. I know where she's going.
但是放心好了  我知道他们的目的地
Eh? Where?
诶  是哪里
Japan.
日本
(Two Months Later)
两个月后
(Shinichi, where are you? Please contact me! Contact me as soon as you see this!)
新一你在哪儿？请联系我 不对 快联系我！
(Shin-chan's kid clothes)
小新的儿童服
Conan Edogawa?
江户川柯南
You know, the boy with glasses! The one I mentioned to you before!
就是之前跟你提过的那个戴眼镜的男孩子
And you said you'd go
你不是说你也有事
visit someone in the Beika district.
去拜访米花町的某人家了吗
Yeah. Shinichi Kudo.
啊  工藤新一吧
Yeah. That's the boy with the detective agency in the same neighborhood.
对  就是那附近的侦探事务所里的那个孩子
So what's with that boy?
那孩子怎么了吗
Something's not right!
总觉得有些不对劲
He's really calm and collected for a child,
明明是小孩  却异常的冷静
almost like an adult.
不如说是像大人
Oh, I see!
原来如此